Arnau Manyosa-Plaza

Frontend Developer & UIUX Designer



Professional with more than 10 years of experience in kicking off and scaling existing cross-platform digital products, focusing on creating meaningful experiences through good design and development. Observer, Emphatic and a team-player personality define me.

arnau.manyosa@protonmail.com arnau.me

EXPERIENCE

Frontend Developer Witty Works AG

July 2021 - Present

I'm the first developer of Witty, a multiplatform browser extension that teaches and suggests users how to write more inclusively.

Technologies: React, Typescript, SASS, REST

Personal/Training break

May 2019 - June 2021

UI/UX Designer & Frontend Developer IBM Research

March 2016 - April 2019

I participated in the Crystal + project, a Natural Language Search Engine solution to identify clients patterns and insights for Enterprise sales and business development. My work focused on transforming a poor search experience and making the represented data more understandable.

Technologies: Angular, Polymer/Web Components, SASS.

Frontend Developer FLX Labs

June 2015 - February 2016

I collaborated in multiple B2C web projects (corporate, ecommerce, microsites), helping and advising external designers on how to transform their work into the final website. Technologies: jQuery, SASS.

Frontend Developer/Lead Frontend Developer Hult IBS

July 2013 - June 2014 - January 2015

I was part of the team responsible for developing the new corporate site for Hult, creating an optimized frontend on top of a Sitecore CMS. Together with a group of designers and marketing experts, we increased the number of leads, registrations and student enrolled.

Technologies: jQuery, CSS, Sitecore, SQL.

EDUCATION

Certified Professional for UX

UXQB

Zürich, Switzerland. 2019

BS in Multimedia Engineering,

La Salle School of Engineering, Barcelona, Spain. 2000 – 2010

Applications Developer Degree

IES Terrassa Technical School Terrassa, Spain. 1998 - 2000

Music Degree

Victoria dels Angels School Sant Cugat, Spain. 1990 - 2002

LANGUAGES

Catalan Native

Spanish Native

English Fluent

German Level A2-B1

REFERENCES

Can be provided as needed

UI/UX Designer & Software Developer Sanovation

June 2012 - March 2013

I was involved in the release of the first version of CatchMyPain for tablets and web platforms. Using a User-Centered Design approach I was responsible for the design of the UI from early prototypes, from the data gathered interviewing real patients and the insights from doctors. I also helped implementing several parts of the UI using Sencha Framework.

Technologies: Javascript, Sencha Touch, CSS, Android, iOS.

SKILLS

Programming

Usability Testing

HTML	 React	
CSS/SASS	 Typescript	
Javascript	 AngularJS/Angular	•
Git	 Node.js	•
Design & Methodologies		
User Analysis & Personas	 Sketch/Figma	
User Journeys & Experience Maps	inVision	
Prototyping & User Interface Design	 Adobe (Photoshop, Illustrator, After Effects, etc)	
Usability & Heuristic Evaluation	 Agile	